Kevin Adrián Rodríguez Ruiz

Full stack developer

About me

Chemical engineer with a MEng in computing with more than four years of experience in software development.

Experience with Web applications, Python, Java, Spring Framework, Nodejs, Amazon Web Services and VSTO Addins

I am excited about integrating multiple disciplines and making things easier and accessible to people.

Interests

Software development, Data analysis, Bioinformatics, Phenomena Modelling and Optimization.

Learning new engineering/science topics.

Languages

Spanish (native) English (fluent) French (basic)

Contact

Bogotá, Colombia. 111156 (+57 1) 6698229 (+57) 3057052399 karodriguezr@unal.edu.co LinkedIn profile GitHub public repositories

SKILLS

Java, Javascript, Html, Node.js, Python, Django Framework, Reactjs, Amazon Web Services, VBA, Spring Framework, Git, VSTO Add-ins, Postgres, MongoDB, Rest, NoSQL, Scrum, Docker.

Programs: MS Excel, Intellij Idea, Aspen Plus.

EXPERIENCE

Consultant (Amaris Consulting, 2019)

+ Oficina en línea. Full stack developer. Web application for the management of insurance policies. Technologies: Reactjs, Redux, Serverless, Amazon Web Services (Lambda, API Gateway, Redis, Dynamodb).

Software Engineer (Pontificia Universidad Javeriana, 2018 - 2019)

+ ANSEP. Astrocyte Neuron Simulation Environment Platform. Design and development. Web platform for the analysis of genome-scale metabolic reconstruction related to the study of neurodegenerative diseases. Technologies: Python, R, Django, Reactjs, Docker, Postgres.

Systems Analyst (Software Colombia SAS, 2015 - 2018)

- + SCmail. Design, development and maintenance. Massive email marketing platform. Technologies: Java, Spring Framework, Nodejs, Gradle, Amazon Web Services (EC2, Lambda, S3, Dynamodb, SES, Autoscale, CodeDeploy, SQS).
- + SCmail upClient. Development and maintenance. Desktop application for the upload of directories/files from a local drive to a repository on Amazon S3. Technologies: Java, JavaFX, Amazon STS.
- + Elogic Monitor. Design, development and support. Desktop application for the generation of digital signatures, encryption, and files upload, it can be invoked from all web browsers. Technologies: Javascript, Java and JavaFX.
- + Edocument. Development. Document management system created to supply the need of encryption operations and digital signature and requiring ensure authenticity during document flows. Based on Nuxeo (Java EE).

Academic projects (2017-2019)

- + Rescurves. Design and development. Open source MS Excel Add-in aimed to ease the three-dimensional plotting of residue curves maps for quaternary systems. Technologies: C#, VSTO.
- + Master's final work: CAMD. Design and development. Desktop application to solve the Computer Aided Molecular Design (CAMD) problem of finding the most suitable solvent for a liquid-liquid separation. It makes use of multi-objective optimization and databases mining algorithms. Technologies: Java, Mongodb.

Freelance (Fall 2016)

+ Traveloso. Development. Mobile applications intended to monitoring drivers via one mobile application. Technologies: Ionic, Spring Boot.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

2016 - present	M. Eng. in Systems Engineering and Computing
	Universidad Nacional de Colombia (Colombia)
2009 - 2015	Exchange Student for the MSc in Advanced Catalysis and Mo-
	lecular Modelling
	Universitat de Girona (Spain)
2009 - 2015	Bachelor's degree in Chemical Engineering
	Universidad Nacional de Colombia (Colombia)